NICHOLAS CALDWELL

Full Stack Software Engineer

CONTACT

nicholas.l.caldwell90@gmail.com

404-487-6597

Columbus, GA

LinkedIn III

Github G

EDUCATION

Certificate Software Development Immersive General Assembly June 2021 – September 2021 Boston, MA

COURSES

Web Development Fundamentals: Unix, Git, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Ajax, Authentication, Sass, Bootstrap Express & MongoDB:

Node, Mongodb, Express API

CS, Python & Django: Computer Science Basics, Python, SQL, Django

SKILLS

Programming: JavaScript HTML/CSS Python (Django) SOL Mongodb Mongoose Express Bootstrap React

> Other: Photoshop Lightroom Excel

SUMMARY

I'm excited to start a new career in tech that will allow me to contribute to the world around me in a positive way. I welcome the opportunity to start down a new path knowing I bring with me 9 years of leadership experience crossing continental borders as well as cultural and language barriers, 12 years of experience in high stress environments with short no fail deadlines, and a lifetime of perseverance and resilience.

PROJECTS

Card PT Workout App

Creator 5-10 AUG 2021

- Created the backend API using Express, Mongoose and Mongodb
- Used JavaScript, HTML/CSS and JQuery to create the responsive

Social Media for Musicians

Team Member / Creator 24-30 AUG 2021

- Utilized pair programing to set up the Mongodb database using Mongoose and Express
- Utilized MOB programing to style our front end using REACT.
- Created our logo using Photoshop
- Conducted final QA to ensure we met all project requirements resulting in 9 missed requirements being found and corrected before the project deadline.

Typing Practice for Coding Language Specific Syntax

Creator 15-21 SEP 2021

Used: Python (Django), PostgreSQL, JS, React, HTML/CSS

WORK EXPERIENCE

US Army 2010 - Current

Training Manager (D Troop, 2nd Squadron, 15th Cavalry Regiment) AUG 2019 - Current / Fort Benning, GA

- Tracked training status of 600+ trainees over 4 training cycles to determine progression and retainability.
- Enabled the organization to reduce manning in the Training Management Department down to one person by using my knowledge of technologies such as Excel, Word and Adobe to streamline the organization's processes including training tracking systems, trainee transition to full time employment, retraining and termination processes, and employee record management systems.

Senior Team Lead (HHC, 3rd Battalion | 5th Infantry Regiment) JUL 2017 – AUG 2019 / Fort Stewart, GA

- Managed a team of 12+ made up of two shift leaders and 10+ junior employees, with oversight of scheduling, daily tasks, physical training, equipment maintenance and training management, planning and execution.
- Mentored 6+ subordinate leaders through verbal and written counseling and training.
- Advised senior leaders during operation planning, delegation and execution.

Operations Assistant Manager (7th Infantry Division)

SEP 2016 – JUL 2017 / Fort Lewis, WA

- Tracked all training and deployments for 8 Brigades
- Ensured proper maintenance of 15+ vehicles
- Facilitated three meetings a week for senior leaders, ensuring all information from all 8 Brigades was current.

Security Specialist & Maintenance Manager (7th Infantry Division)

MAR 2015 – SEP 2016 / Kandahar Airfield, Afghanistan

- Trained and managed 3 iterations of Romanian security forces to secure the organization's compound
- Managed all maintenance requests and oversaw work order completion by foreign nationals on all the organizations facilities made up of 25 office buildings and two security checkpoints.

Team Leader (A Troop, 3rd Squadron, 38th Cavalry Regiment) SEP 2013 – MAR 2015 / Fort Lewis, WA

- Managed a team of 6+ made up of two shift leaders and 4+ junior employees with oversight of scheduling, daily tasks, physical training, equipment maintenance and training management, planning and execution.
- Mentored 2+ subordinate leaders through verbal and written counseling and training.

Shift Leader (A Troop, 3rd Squadron, 38th Cavalry Regiment) APR 2013 – SEP 2013 / Fort Lewis, WA

- Mentored 3+ employees, developing and honing their technical and leadership skills through counseling sessions, utilizing a standard counseling form.
- Oversaw daily tasks for a team of three including, vehicle and weapon maintenance, skill building, physical training and personal readiness management.